Syracuse Sheet Music Collection
Syracuse Sheet Music Collection
1847-1919
1 folder (ovesize portfolio)
Sheet music printed in Syracuse, New York; many items include advertisements for local businesses
4609633
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Syracuse Sheet Music Collection consists of specimens of sheet music printed in Syracuse, New York. Many of the items include advertisements for local area businesses, both music-related and non-music-related.
Arrangement of the Collection
Alphabetical by author.
Related Material
For additional material relating to music in Syracuse, see also the
Melville Clark Papers
and the
Clark Music Company Records
. For additional material relating to early Syracuse-area businesses, using these keywords: syracuse commerce.
Subject and Genre Headings
Music; New York State; Publishing, printing and book arts; Clark Music Company (Syracuse, N.Y.); Business enterprises -- New York (State) -- History.; Syracuse (N.Y.) -- Commerce.; Advertisements.; Sheet music.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Purchase, 2015.
Inventory
- Sheet music
  - Ball, Charles, "The Apollo March and Two Step," Clark Music Co., 1906; back has full-page ad for Apollo Player Pianos (Oversize 1)
  - Ball, Charles, "Daughter of Pocahontas," Leiter Bros., 1909; back cover includes full-page ad for Leiter Bros. shop on South Salina St. (Oversize 1)
  - Ball, Charles, "The Herald March," Leiter Bros., 1895; "Dedicated to the Syracuse Evening Herald" (Oversize 1)
  - Bugbee, Willis N, and Weaver, T. B., "Just Smile and Say Good-Bye," The Willis N. Bugbee Co., 1919 (Oversize 1)
  - Davis, Daisy M., "Ka-Noo-Noo Maid," Clark Engraving Co. and The Dehler Printing Co., 1912 (Oversize 1)
  - Davis, F. and Gleason, M., "I'm Glad I'm Back in Syracuse," Rudolph Bros., 1912; back cover includes photo of The Novelty Shop on South Salina St. (Oversize 1)
  - Lederman, Phillip, "Pleasant Beach Two-Step," M. L. Mantell, 1847; front cover has black-and-white photo of Pleasant Beach Hotel in Fair Haven, New York; back cover has excerpt of Scott Joplin piece, "Please Say You Will" (Oversize 1)
  - Payne, John Howard, "Home Sweet Home," Peerless B Edition, 1847; front cover has advertising for Mertens, Yann & Garnett Clothiers in the Everson Building (Oversize 1)
  - Miscellaneous, one leaf of unidentified music; three leaves with advertisements for local Syracuse businesses, including Cotharin & Ball, Talbot's Temperance Hotel, Lazier's Photography, Brewster's Dry Goods, Sabey & Company Hatters and Furriers, and many more; booklet, "Souvenir Music Compliments of D. McCarthy & Co." apparently from their "Great Opening," containing advertisements and music (Oversize 1)